Moushumi Das

SUMMARY

2+ years of experience of object-oriented programming. Experienced in collecting, interpreting and analyzing sophisticated data in order to make successful strategic planning and improvement in research. Worked successfully in high-pressure environments by adapting to changing situations, communicating effectively with co-workers and multitasking when necessary.

SKILLS

Front-end: React, HTML, CSS/SCSS, JavaScript ES5, ES6, jQuery, AJAX. **Back-end:** NodeJS, Python, SQL, C++, RESTful API, Entity Framework, JSON.

Database: MongoDB, Firebase, MySQL.

Concepts & Tools: Git bash, Git hub, shell, Yarn, Webpack

PROJECTS

Project 1 | Demo Link: Real-time food ordering application

Technologies: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node.js, Express.js and MongoDB.

- Built a Real time food ordering web application where customer can track the status of their order in real time
- The application comes with user authentication and order history.
- Customized dashboard for user and admin.
- Deployed on Heroku

Project 2 | Demo Link: Blog Application

Technologies: React, React-router, Redux, Node.js, MongoDB.

- Created a single page blog application where users can add, modify and delete their post. Users can modify their profile and can upload their photo as well.
- Posts, users are stored in MongoDB database.
- Deployed on Heroku.

Project 3 | GitHub Link: Real-time chat application

Technologies: HTML, CSS, Express, Node.js, JavaScript, Socket.io.

- Created a real-time chat app with a custom UI.
- Users can join in different chat rooms.

Project 4 | GitHub Link: House Price Prediction API

Technologies: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Flask.

- Created a Flask API along with an HTML application that is developed to interact with the best machine learning model.
- Users can directly input information through the UI and check the house price.

EXPERIENCE

Operation Specialist | SkipTheDishes

OCT 2020- Present

- Efficiently provides live support to stakeholders through verbal and written forms of communication.
- Appropriately escalates situations where the stakeholder is dealing with advanced issues.
- Provides the best possible solutions to clients through utilizing analytical skills and extensive knowledge of organizational processes.
- Manages client data and updates customer files with the most recent information pertaining to account changes, operations, and financial options.

Research Assistant | University of Manitoba

SEP 2017- FEB 2019

- Built a data collection and analyzing system using Python which successfully reduced the data collection time by 50%.
- Developed substantial experience with error handling, unit testing and documentation through working on multiple projects collaboratively with colleagues.
- Effectively used Source Version Control-Git for continuous integration and maintenance of different versions of source code.

EDUCATION

Node.js Full-stack web development | ComIT APRIL 2021 – JULY 2021

MSC in Physics | University of Manitoba SEPTEMBER 2016 – FEBRUARY 2019

REFERENCES

Available upon request